it's not for the first time markets have
fallen like this if one looks at the
last 20 years of data concentrated sell
offs have happened in the past but what
I want to discuss with Mr contrarian on
the show today which is s narain is that
when markets fall like this should one
uh start praying and remembering their
favorite God or it is time now to put
money to work what are the chances that
if you buy now you may not end up buying
a falling knife you may actually buying
value and this could be a great entry
point when a ShakeOut has actually
happened both locally and globally nin
fantastic to have you back thank you for
joining us you love these days don't you
yeah they give you buying opportunity to
buy I love Friday more were you buyer
last week were you buyer last Friday
yeah actually we've created a set of
products like balanced Advantage fund uh
which you know basically makes use of
these opportunities to buy and uh you
know we inherently believe that markets
will be volatile and and uh will give
you such
opportunities and uh the Beauty has been
that like you know in the last one let's
say 45 days both uh on the last day of
the month in uh January on the February
1st and on February 28th we got superb
opportunities to buy and in both the
days markets actually came so fast that
you got a superb opportunity to buy and
these kind of opportunities when there
is panic and you have the ability to buy
gives you a very interesting
situation then it is said that markets
always preem the future it is collective
wisdom and markets will tell you what is
going to happen next the fall what we've
seen last week at least in global
markets is reminiscent of the price
action we've seen in 2008 this is not
2008 this is not a problem where a
system is going to collapse but yet the
selling has been very concentrated and
very excruciating what does the pattern
tell you see actually you know the fact
is you go and look at the chart of many
of the global uh stock indices let's
take the NASDAQ index the NASDAQ index
has been moving a parabolic moves when
you have parabolic moves upward you have
to have a reason for a correction when
you see that correction actually you'll
realize that uh there was need for a
correction what that correction reason
is you will realize it later you will
not know it on that day and uh what we
always say is you know triggers are
found later we will realize that the
trigger is uh Corona virus but no one
would know what is the reason but uh if
you look at any of the global large cap
tech stocks you'll find that theyve gone
a parabolic moves so why can't there be
a correction and if markets were to just
go up and actually if you look at the
lead reason for the markets going up if
you look at it you have taken interest
rates to zero you have made the cost of
holding Equity zero when you make the
cost of holding Equity zero doesn't make
Equity becomes riskless so these
periodic Corrections are needed to prove
that there is something required called
an equity risk premium and that is what
has been proved at this point of time
over the last two weeks there's a
thought in the market Nar which is that
in 2008 Central Bankers came together
they cut interest rates down guess what
for anyone to cut rates now scope is not
there us bond yield is at 1% in Japan
negative interest rates have been there
for years now Europe also where interest
rates are so if there is a problem of
growth in the world what is the
ammunition left in anybody's uh you know
Armory to fix the problem see while that
is true of most countries us can cut
interest rates by 1% India can cut
interest rates by more than 5% so I
would say us and India are in a much
much better position than most of
countries in the world so I would say
that from that point of view I would say
that India and us are in a much better
position uh clearly that is true but if
you look at a country like Germany it's
fiscally balanced so frankly if one day
German Parliament wakes up and says we
have to do fiscal stimulus they can
actually increase their fiscal deficit
uh so there is possibility of fiscal
stimulus in Germany there is a
possibility of rates to be cut
significantly in India
these are the things which can happen
pretty easily at this point of time so
the question will just come up on the
screen as we you know walk and as we
talk which is that is this risk is this
volatility I would call it volatility
and volatility when valuations are high
is part of the game and people think
that there won't be volatility in equity
markets they have to be periodically
told that volatility is there if
volatility never comes like
2017 people think why should I invest in
debt why should I invest in large cap
let's choose only small cap I think
these periodic bouts of volatility are
necessary for people to actually uh feel
that they should be actually having an
asset allocation approach to investing
and not just investing only in equity so
I think it's a good wakeup call for
people and uh it actually makes the
market more sensible investors more
sensible fund managers more sensible
issuers more sensible everybody becomes
more sensible okay so let's talk about
your investment style you love bad news
because bad news gives you better value
where do you think markets currently
have overshot themselves and the
underlying asset pricing either is cheap
or the underlying business is not that
bad I think value was cheap ahead of the
correction but value is corrected as
much as other stocks so I find it you
know in my investing career I saw stocks
on dividend deal cheap in 20012 and
after that for a 6mon period after lemon
I again see a number of stocks very
cheap on dividend de when stocks are
very cheap on dividend deal it gives me
the ability to buy and hold if dividend
yield in a country like India is equal
to let's say liquid fund returns it
gives me the chance to buy that stock
and sit on it for the next 3 years
because I feel that I can hold on to the
stock because in addition to Dividend
yeld at some point of time I should get
cap capital appreciation and that
becomes a big Advantage so I think there
is deep value today in a number of
stocks and what what I find amazing they
are available in a number of large cap
stocks as well and that has become a big
Advantage for me it is there in many of
the psus it's there in many of the oil
stocks it's there in many of the metal
stocks it is there in a wide number of
stocks at this point of time is
different investing a good old value
investing debt the reason why I'm saying
this is because that theorem of value
investing where you buy cheap hold focus
on the underlying asset Price look at
the Enterprise Value last 10 years these
theorems have not made money are you are
you getting old now to understand the
new world this is a question I'm being
asked periodically in 199 ask in 1999
Warren Buffett was asked this question
so I read the recent annual report of
workshire haway statement he has
underperformed the Benchmark in
2019 and his statement uh and you know
in 1999 he was written off 2019 years
underperform Benchmark meaningfully so
after that uh Warren Buffett will is
also being asked this question so he
comes back from the grave always and
shows that value investing works I don't
think uh that's largely because interest
rates always go up and down and then it
changes the way you price the asset but
in this case interest rates I mean
permanently down and they may remain low
for long so how does one invest in this
kind of an environment but if dividend
yield is much higher than interest rates
why can't dividend deal compensate for
the low interest rates doesn't mean that
you can have markets just going up skyh
high it can't happen that's my view and
uh that is the way if you look at it uh
it has not proved right that over the
last 20 30 years there was a period
between 96 and 99 where people
pronounced value investing Deb but value
investing came from the grave between 99
and 2007 again in the last 3 4 years I
was reading one prominent fund house
which said it was again a tough time for
Value investors but they come back
because end of the day it is a style
which has proved its existence for the
last 50 60 years so I don't think it'll
go out of fashion I think it'll come
back always because it is logic uh when
it works in in buying vegetables it
works in buying cars why won't it work
in buying stocks also over the long term
so can I say sarin feel that it's time
to buy PSU stocks sarin feel it's time
to buy oil PSU stocks it's time time to
buy utilities time to buy metal stocks
time to buy dividend deal stocks time to
buy metal stocks time to buy anything
where the intrinsic value looks this
thing the same thing worked one year
back people used to ask me will Telecom
ever deliver and people used to ask us
whether corporate banks will ever
deliver but today the question on
Telecom and corporate banks have ceased
to exist because they have delivered so
once something delivers people stop
asking that question once it doesn't Del
people ask you this question it's part
of the job when you're managing other
people's money you have to be willing to
ask these answer these questions because
you are handling other people's money
and the problem is we don't control the
markets we only control the philosophy
and the process and I believe that uh
the long-term investors today in value
funds today are going to have a
phenomenal time is my personal belief
your lucky charm in last two years has
been telom you started buying Telcom
stocks in 2018 you held on to your
conviction 2019 is where you've made
money when you bought telecom stocks
your theory what my understanding is
that you thought that rates will not
remain that low and eventually industry
will come back in terms of uh coming to
reasonable pricing but when you invested
in telom stocks I'm sure the a AGR issue
was not on the horizon yes so how would
you view telecom stocks considering that
there is an AGR issue on the horizon so
I think it has made the outlook for the
top two stocks more beneficial uh I
would hope to still see a three player
Market because I think a country like
India requires a three player Market but
I would say that if you have a
two-player Market the outlook for the
two players become Superior to that of a
three player Market but I think the
Outlook depends finally it depends on
how important the mobile phone is for
you today if you look at what has
happened after Corona virus travel is
completely suspended but events still go
everything happens now on video
conference if you look at what is
happening in equity research every
Global house today does video
conferences equivalent to research
visits and every day I get mail saying
that these are the five video
conferences we are organizing what does
it mean more revenue for Telecom and
lesser revenue for all the other
Industries no but I would insist you
come to our studio every
time soly let's be very sure that you
know what you know demand or I request
from you always has been it's much more
interactive that's what I always feel
I'm going to switch gears and talk about
something where you've invested in the
past you took a big bet on Tata group of
names when Chandra took over uh how
would you view things and how are they
moving for the Tata group se's
restriction is on stocks not on
groups see it's see finally at the end
of the day you know a group depends on
the sectors and that's why it's
difficult to classify it on the basis of
a group I would say that there have been
challenges on anything to do with
infrastructure and uh I believe that if
I look at it I have a principle if for
10 12 years an industry does badly you
bet on the all the companies in that
industry which you think Will Survive
just say that again if IND industry does
badly for 10 12 years you bet on all the
companies which you think Will Survive
that was my goal in Telecom also today
today not withstanding ESG my belief is
that if you are dependent on power you
bet on Renewable Power how many people
are there renewable par today can you
live without Park can you live without
Telecom you can't live without power and
renew and Telecom so I believe that you
have to bet on all the people whom you
think will survive in power industry are
there how many people are surviving in
the power industry less than 1 fth of
the number of people who existed in 2007
is the outlook for that 1if much better
than what it was certainly because uh
Power demand keeps going up in the next
10 years 20 years will power demand go
up it'll go up so I a big believer that
in any sector you have to bet on the
survivors and that is proved even in
corporate banking it's proved in Telecom
it will prove itself in power can there
be ESG problems in Coal Power it can be
but is Renewable Power how many people
are in Renewable Power who all are in
Renewable Power look at it from that
angle so I would say you have to go
across each specific company if a
company has good corporate govern group
has good corporate governance they will
choose not to move money from one place
to another so which means you can have
companies doing well you can have
companies not doing well and that's part
of the job so our job is to choose the
sectors doing well finally at the end of
the day we have to choose sectors not
doing well and hope for it to do well
and that's how we try to make money what
are the lessons for an investor to be
learned when you see a stock like demart
which was expensive go from uh the
listing price not the IPO price the
listing day price of 600 to 2500 I think
the final answer will be in
2025 okay the answer will not be in 2020
because finally our belief is what we
saw from even credit risk funds see it
is not in 2017 without credit risk
playing out that you analyzed who won or
who lost we have not seen an equity
cycle go away yet the cycle which
started in 2014 is continuing in 2020
the equity Market bull market which
started in 2012 and us is continuing in
2020 so I believe the time to look at
investing is after a cycle is over and I
believe that that's why I would say the
best time to evaluate any company is
when you look at it over a cycle because
in a part of the cycle when there is a
bull market particularly Financial
Services if you look at it if you look
at one part of the cycle you'll think
that someone is the winner once the
credit cycle turns up someone else
becomes the winner and that's what we'
have seen in different parts of
different indust we don't know where and
how the next bull market is coming we
don't know which stock could be in a
bull market or a bare Market that's
price action what I guess fund managers
try to analyze is where there could be
earnings uptick and where there could be
C cyclical up it could be market share
gain it could be industry disruption
where do you think what are the two or3
Trends according to you are going to be
the powerful trends for 20 from 2020 to
20 2 on earnings on market share gain or
even on disruption I think people seem
to think that all that is required is
the quality ends of the spectrum and
people seem to think that it is people
can do with only quality stocks I
believe that in 2007 people believed
that you had to have only the infra
oriented stocks I don't think that's
possible what happens is in any industry
if the only one set of companies enter
in in for example in 2007 you had 25
Road companies entering you had 25
companies entering power sector today
for example no one is entering Telecom
no one is entering power no one is
entering different Industries so what
happens the number of players in every
industry keeps going down when the
number of Industry players go down the
margins for the players increase so I
believe you have to bet on the
industries which have done too badly for
12 years and for me it's a very good
situation that if there there are
sectors which have done very badly or
big themes which have done badly for 10
12 years and you're not going to have a
country which can only do well with only
one theme playing out it can't happen a
big country cannot play with just one
theme we are not a nation state a nation
state like Hong Kong and Singapore can
have one theme just playing out we can't
do it we are a big country so I believe
we bet on themes which have not played
out for 10 12 years and bet on that
theme that's how we look at it every
time when we look at the last 10 year
and then we in a sense look at uh the
future 10 years there are businesses
which are relevant and there are
businesses which may not be relevant in
today's disruptive world when we using
words like artificial intelligence how
3D printing and 3D manufacturing is
changing the way how we would be
consuming which other business you think
will not be relevant I mean ultimately
we have to figure out whether the
importance of that business or the need
of that business will be there in the
society or not and the reason why I'm
asking you this is that you give me a
wonderful example in 2017 when we met at
the Morning Star conference and you said
look this is my phone and I'm spending 3
hours with this phone 3 hours on my
phone every day so the relevance of
Telecom services will not go away apart
from Telecom which are the businesses
which you think will lose relevance or
will or relevance will increase for them
it's something that we have to keep
thinking about I mean how you and I live
each day and how we act like if you look
at it you know the reality is that when
I see the younger generation I am
dependent on reading Economic Times in
the morning and Times of India in the
morning but look at the younger
generation they want to read it on their
app so that's how the younger generation
wants to read everything on an app
whereas I want to read that print copy
every day in the morning so that's a
change in Trend so I believe like that
there are many things that you know
which the younger generation likes to do
on their phone what the older generation
likes to do physically so like I'm used
to doing everything on my mobile
application on the bank but my
mother-in-law doesn't like to T she
believes that if she uses our mobile
application our money in our bank
account will disappear so that is why
she doesn't touch the mobile application
so I think we have to look at how all of
us use change how we have changed our
lives over a period of time can we live
how we change how we have changed
everything can I go to the theater and
book a ticket no it's not possible I
today we have to B at our homes and then
go to the theater you know you're giving
a lot of respect to mother-in-law so I
can guess that you have a very happy
marriage so n I'm going to shift gears
and again talk about Metals there's lot
of gloom and doom in the world because
of the way China is going to move you
bought Metals in the past you bought
Metals in the past when macros has
become bad and rupee has depreciated
will that same theorem apply this time
the same theorem will apply but you know
the reality is Haven made money the
reality is that baring the only time in
2015 when we bought and we sold a part
of it in
2016 the rest of the time it has not
made money for us that is a reality but
the reality is can we grow without metal
consumption going up the answer is that
the market seems to think that only soap
demand has to go up it believes that
toothpaste demand and soap demand and
cloth demand will go up but there is no
requirement for Metals in India that I
think is irrational because you know
without steel demand or aluminium demand
going up there you can't have a
situation that uh only only certain
demands go up and the rest of the demand
go up today is it possible to put up a
steel plant in India I think it's
impossible to put up a steel plant in
India I think these are the
imponderables which we see at this point
of time gives us lot of scope to make
these what I believe is there are one
set of stock with implied assump
there are another set of stock with
another set of implied assumptions what
we tried to do is we move from the stock
with very low implied assumptions we
move to those stocks from the stocks
with very high implied assumptions this
is what we did in 2007 the point is
people ask when is the turning point I
don't know the turning point but I have
to bet against the turning point I have
to do it before the turning point
because if I try to wait for that
turning point I can't do it on the way
down but n do you enjoy being a contan
then I'm saying this that HDFC bank or
private sector Banks they were a crowded
trade in 2005 2010 2015 and 20120 and
for those who said look I will not go
down the value chain in buying PSU Banks
they've got it right so it's a popular
call but the popular call has worked
what are the chances that next 5 years
popular calls will work because popular
calls are the ones where growth is there
so popular calls with Fair valuation we
are not opposed to you'll have to look
at the top Holdings of our company to
know what are the popular calls which we
believe are fairly valued where we are
invested discuss give me a sense as not
about a company not about in Banks we
have popular calls which are fairly
valued like corporate Banks like
corporate Banks Telcom has become a
popular call popular call fairly valued
we do have them you think telom and
corporate banks have a long way to go
yes because they are basic human
Necessities where there is a certain
amount of benefit for the I would say
that the larger companies have their
comparative advantages typically in a
year how many stocks do you buy or sell
see we have number of funds the the
schemes which you manage I mean we would
end up buying 20 or 30 stocks at least
maybe even more because we have smaller
stocks so it could be larger and that's
how we do it because will it be more
will it be few what will be the mantra
for your AMC in next couple of years see
we are not a niche AMC we run schemes
from small caps to Mega caps so it's not
not uh that's not our goal our goal is
to be a trusted asset management company
for millions of Indians with that goal
we can't afford to say we'll do only a
few things okay when we spoke last you
spoke about it's time to start a sip in
small cap funds now that price
dislocation has happened whenever
recovery will happen small caps will
lack the recovery that's how markets are
moved in the past it doesn't change our
sip call in small caps it just doesn't
change our incidentally in the last 3
months small caps have done very well
compared to large caps but it doesn't
change our sip call at all this's Mega
concentration which is happening in
large cap stocks is it because of lack
of ideas low risk or uh this is
something which is here to stay it is
past returns forcing people into
concentration where are you on this ESG
theme because I get a sense from Global
Investors and especially hedge funds and
also Sovereign funds that we don't want
to touch anything which is polluting the
environment which is causing harm to the
environment the millions are getting
more conscious you know I walked to a
coffee store today they don't give me a
plastic spoon they give me a wooden
spoon now how are you looking at
investing in this theme because Larry FL
has started talking about it now JP
Morgan has started talking about it now
at ICC potential MC how are you betting
on the I think we are in the initial
stages we'll be moving forward in it and
uh we will look at it on a holistic
basis the model is very funny people say
oil is okay but coal is not okay in my
opinion uh you know there are so many
areas where people choose what they feel
is fine uh what is g what is appropriate
governance these are all questions which
will come out and uh I think the whole
process has started and I think uh this
area will evolve over a period of time I
think uh I think this area is in its
infancy in India and it'll keep
improving over the next 3 to 5 years if
you have to summarize the today's
interaction can I safely say that you
feel this is not end of a bull market
and this is not beginning of a bare
Market yeah I believe we are in a
moderate return world and I continue to
think that in this moderate return World
there are opportunities there is a wide
Divergence between one set of stocks and
another that has not got corrected in
this correction so till that gets
corrected I don't think we are in a
phase where we can say that the entire
Market can move to a high return World
well really appreciate thank you for
joining us
[Music]